<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on Arian&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://arianv.com/tags/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on Arian&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 10:48:18 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://arianv.com/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Month with Vim</title>
      <link>http://arianv.com/post/My-First-Month-with-Vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 10:48:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arianv.com/post/My-First-Month-with-Vim/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Today celebrates my first month with vim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also marks the first time I did a custom configuration on my &lt;code&gt;.vimrc&lt;/code&gt;. When I said &amp;lsquo;custom&amp;rsquo; it means that it was not just some snippet I found from the internet, it was an actual, personal configuration that made &amp;lsquo;vim&amp;rsquo; my own flavor of &amp;lsquo;vim&amp;rsquo;. This, I think, is the point when someone can say they have graduated from vim noob, to vim user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;hipster-coding:c0f0488411cf8fe53e5c18f05ae3dc22&#34;&gt;Hipster Coding&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vim is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; editor. Not just any editor. &lt;strong&gt;THE&lt;/strong&gt; editor. You know for &lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/378/&#34;&gt;real programmers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a couple of months ago I made the switch from Windows to OSX, biting the bullet and buying myself a 13&amp;rdquo; rMBP. I&amp;rsquo;ve come to enjoy the transition thus far, finally having the versatility of UNIX on my machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more than positive experience of switching OS made me want to experiment with my tools more, and seeing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UTqZNujQOlA&#34;&gt;Jonathan Blow programming on Emacs&lt;/a&gt; inspired me to switch to these classic editors. I already used Emacs back in the day, and while it is a good editor, I was looking for something a little more lightweight and nimble. Working with Javascript most of the time, I would much prefer a speedy editor like Vim against fancy IDE features that Emacs could offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-learning-curve-and-progressive-hacking:c0f0488411cf8fe53e5c18f05ae3dc22&#34;&gt;The Learning Curve and Progressive Hacking&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was intimidated at first. Vim is well known to have a pretty brutal learning curve, and I had contracts whose deadlines won&amp;rsquo;t extend to account for me learning a new editor. This was a potential show-stopper right from the get go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>