<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arian&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>//arianv.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Arian&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 10:25:27 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//arianv.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The 4R framework - 3 libraries to use in your React app</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/the-4r-framework-3-libraries-to-use-in-your-react-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 10:25:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/the-4r-framework-3-libraries-to-use-in-your-react-app/</guid>
      <description>React fits well right in to the Unix philosophy - it does one thing, and one thing well. It&amp;rsquo;s a beautifully designed, declarative library for building user interfaces.
To write complex React applications however, it would be best to use more libraries than just React in it&amp;rsquo;s lonesome.
The vast and rapidly evolving javascript landscape means there&amp;rsquo;s almost always a library that we can leverage for any given task. Given that, there are 3 libraries I consider essential when making React apps, and I&amp;rsquo;ve consolidated it to this one catchy name because marketing is everything</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Default HOCs for Component Logic</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/use-default-hocs-for-component-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 12:04:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/use-default-hocs-for-component-logic/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps one of the most useful patterns for writing React applications is the classic &amp;ldquo;Container and Presentational Components&amp;rdquo; pattern. Even without knowledge of React, it makes sense - it decomposes concerns between component presentation and logic.
One very useful pattern I&amp;rsquo;ve used to achieve this is by using Higher Order Components to inject default logic to components. This pattern drastically reduces component API boilerplate and more effectively separates implementation and presentational concerns of components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Module Bundling and Webpack in Simple Terms</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/module-bundling-and-webpack-in-simple-terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 21:22:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/module-bundling-and-webpack-in-simple-terms/</guid>
      <description>#chapter-1, #chapter-2__scroll { display: none; position: relative; height: 100vh; width: 100%; } .chapter-1__heading { font-size: 2rem; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 0; max-width: none !important; position: absolute; text-align: center; width: 100%; } .chapter-1__heading-1 { opacity: 1; } .chapter-1__hider-1, .chapter-1__hider-2, .chapter-1__hider-3, .chapter-1__hider-4 { background-color: #002B36; height: 1rem; position: absolute; width: 100%; } .chapter-2__darkener { background-color: gray; opacity: 0.5; position: absolute; height: 30rem; width: 100%; } .chapter-2__code-file { position: absolute; width: 100%; } .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LearnOverpass Final Report</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/learnoverpass-gsoc-2015-final-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 13:40:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/learnoverpass-gsoc-2015-final-report/</guid>
      <description>This year I participated in my 2nd GSOC journey. I worked for the OpenStreetMap Foundation developing an integrated learning platform for their Overpass API which we (me and my mentor) affectionally called LearnOverpass
It&amp;rsquo;s been three months since I started the project, and LearnOverpass is now live and functional - and while the consensus is still out, I&amp;rsquo;m definitely happy with the results!
Exercises, exercises One of the definite &amp;lsquo;killer features&amp;rsquo; we aimed for in LearnOverpass is the inclusion of interactive, playable exercises - with the goal of introducing users, to the Overpass API through active engagement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LearnOverpass</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/portfolio/learn-overpass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 12:59:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/portfolio/learn-overpass/</guid>
      <description>LearnOverpass is the definitive learning platform for the Overpass Query Language. Worked with the OpenStreetMap Foundation on the Google Summer of Code Program</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liang Court</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/portfolio/liang-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 12:59:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/portfolio/liang-court/</guid>
      <description>A facebook embedded, casino coupon reward game for Liang Court, a Major Mall in Singapore</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polishing API Reference: GSOC Weekly Update 4</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/polishing-api-reference-weekly-update-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 11:27:49 +0801</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/polishing-api-reference-weekly-update-4/</guid>
      <description>This is the fourth weekly update for the LearnOverpass Project.
This week&amp;rsquo;s deliverable is to polish the learning platform&amp;rsquo;s API reference.
Modern Sensibilities The changes required for this week required me to flex my design muscles a bit.
Martin&amp;rsquo;s pull request showed my lack of eye for the site&amp;rsquo;s typography, with what me using a 2.5em line-height.
As the line-height issue was fixed, I also decided to pick a more modern typeface to go along with the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porting API Reference: GSOC Weekly Update 3</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/porting-api-reference-weekly-update-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 13:46:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/porting-api-reference-weekly-update-3/</guid>
      <description>This is the third weekly update for the LearnOverpass Project.
This week&amp;rsquo;s deliverable is to &amp;lsquo;port&amp;rsquo; the API reference to the learning platform.
Existing Resources The &amp;lsquo;sales pitch&amp;rsquo; of LearnOverpass has always been &amp;lsquo;a one stop, learning resource for the overpass API&amp;rsquo; - we wanted the site to be the de facto page for learning the Query Language.
To do this properly, we need to make use of, and expand, existing resources of the language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedding Overpass Turbo: GSOC Weekly Update 2</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/embedding-overpass-turbo-weekly-update-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 15:50:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/embedding-overpass-turbo-weekly-update-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the second weekly update for the LearnOverpass Project.
This week&amp;rsquo;s deliverable is to integrate Overpass Turbo inside the learning platform.
 From the get go, we knew we wanted to bring out a REPL-like interface to LearnOverpass - we want to encourage users to actively try and experiment with the Query Language.
The Overpass API guide in the wiki already knew that seeing the results of the query is useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>series gsoc2015</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/desc/series-gsoc-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 11:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/desc/series-gsoc-2015/</guid>
      <description>In 2015, I worked on the Overpass&amp;rsquo; Learning Platform for Google Summer Of Code 2015. This series details the creation of the project, from the initial project proposal, to the design, technical considerations, implementation, and user feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC 2015 Introduction: LearnOverpass</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/gsoc-2015-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 18:52:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/gsoc-2015-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Last year, I worked with the Wordpress organization to integrate socialization and gamification features to the Glotpress translation platform. It&amp;rsquo;s been a fun fulfilling ride, and there are definitely a lot of things that I learned during the project.
This year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been accepted to Google&amp;rsquo;s Summer of Code Program again and I&amp;rsquo;m working with the OpenStreetMap organization to create LearnOverpass!
What is LearnOverpass The Overpass API is a robust API for querying map data, but it&amp;rsquo;s use is still limited due to its beginner-unfriendly documentation and scarce tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Month with Vim</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/my-first-month-with-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 10:48:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/my-first-month-with-vim/</guid>
      <description>Today celebrates my first month with vim.
It also marks the first time I did a custom configuration on my .vimrc. When I said &amp;lsquo;custom&amp;rsquo; it means that it was not just some snippet I found from the internet, it was an actual, personal configuration that made &amp;lsquo;vim&amp;rsquo; my own flavor of &amp;lsquo;vim&amp;rsquo;. This, I think, is the point when someone can say they have graduated from vim noob, to vim user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excellent Communicator</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/about/communicator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 13:38:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/about/communicator/</guid>
      <description>Excellent Communicator
I&amp;rsquo;m a very chill guy to talk to, and I always try to put myself in other people&amp;rsquo;s shoes.
I write technical articles aimed at the general audience, which have been very well received on sites such as GameDev.net and Gamasutra.
I also maintain my own blog at arianv.com
  &amp;ldquo;Super talented and hard working. Also a super friendly guy who is a frequent communicator.&amp;rdquo; Daniel Stone (Client)   &amp;ldquo;Keep up the good work!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous and Fast Learner</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/about/fastlearner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 13:38:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/about/fastlearner/</guid>
      <description>In Journey East, I was tasked to learn a language I&amp;rsquo;m unfamiliar with (Java) and learn how to develop APIs in a short amount of time so I could be brought to work on the server.
 Spontaneous and Fast Learner
I&amp;rsquo;m a self starter, and thrive in fast-paced, dynamic environments.
I have a knack for learning new technologies in short periods of time.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC 2014 - Wordpress</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/portfolio/gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:55:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/portfolio/gsoc/</guid>
      <description>Worked with the Wordpress Organization on the Google Summer of Code Program to gamify and improve Glotpress</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merc 01</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/portfolio/merc-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:55:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/portfolio/merc-01/</guid>
      <description>A fast paced, action-packed twin stick shooter made in pyglet with custom direct GL drawing for fast performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jSolar</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/portfolio/jsolar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:55:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/portfolio/jsolar/</guid>
      <description>A 3d simulation of the copernican solar system model, where users can move the camera as well as affix it to the different planets. Made with Three.js</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghoul Feeder</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/portfolio/ghoul-feeder/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:54:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/portfolio/ghoul-feeder/</guid>
      <description>Powerup your ghoul in this kid-centric flash game!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Issues</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/portfolio/big-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:53:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/portfolio/big-issues/</guid>
      <description>A &amp;lsquo;Begging Game&amp;rsquo; showing the issues of poverty and world hunger. Developed for the Charity Game Jam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zombie Shooting Game</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/portfolio/zombie-shooting-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:52:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/portfolio/zombie-shooting-game/</guid>
      <description>GPU Accelerated flash game developed with Starling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RUPP</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/portfolio/rupp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:48:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/portfolio/rupp/</guid>
      <description>Fluid Web App built with AngularJS. Complete Route Based Navigations lend to a fluid user experience. NodeJS backend on top of SailsJS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PiRPG</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/portfolio/pirpg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:47:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/portfolio/pirpg/</guid>
      <description>JRPG with a uniquely dynamic card based system. Project Manager, integrated development, art and QA, organizing workload and direction. Responsible for entire engine creation. Code followed best OOP practices to make card functions easily extendable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey East</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/portfolio/journey-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:45:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/portfolio/journey-east/</guid>
      <description>An epic MMO set in an original world, featuring Crafting, Raids, and PvP! Coordinated with a team of developers. Responsible for Client and Server Development. (AS3 and Java)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VirtuaPet</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/portfolio/virtuapet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 19:41:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/portfolio/virtuapet/</guid>
      <description>A Modern Virtual Pet Site where players collect, train, and take care of pets! Written in PHP, made with Love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Match 3</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/portfolio/match-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 13:38:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/portfolio/match-3/</guid>
      <description>HTML5 Matching 3 Game. Set up to communicate with PHP backend for point based earning on Virtual Economy Sites</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orb Knight</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/portfolio/orb-knight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 13:38:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/portfolio/orb-knight/</guid>
      <description>Orb Knight-RPG, Featuring pets and a Realtime Battle System. Made for Google HTML5 Game Making Contest</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scratch Wars</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/portfolio/scratch-wars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 13:38:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/portfolio/scratch-wars/</guid>
      <description>Control your forces in this epic battle between Red and Blue!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space Shooter</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/portfolio/space-shooter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 13:38:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/portfolio/space-shooter/</guid>
      <description>Mobile Friendly Shooter built on top of the Phaser Framework. Features powerups and an online leaderboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Ability</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/about/codesample/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 13:38:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/about/codesample/</guid>
      <description>Solid Software Engineering Skills.
Familiar with numerous programming paradigms such as Object-Oriented, Functional, and Asynchronous Programming.
 #dev-ops workflow.use gulp or grunt workflow.use stylus or sass or less workflow.use imagemin # #agile listenTo(SpecChange, -&amp;gt; applyChanges() )

  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>