<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Arian&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>//arianv.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Arian&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 13:18:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//arianv.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CS 180 Pathfinding</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/cs-180-pathfinding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 13:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/cs-180-pathfinding/</guid>
      <description>In my CS 180 (Artificial Intelligence class), I was tasked to implement search algorithms for pathfinding. This post series is a direct conversion of the jupyter notebooks for that project.
The jupyter notebooks can be found online here
CS 180 Artificial Intelligence&amp;#182;Machine Problem 1: Path Planning&amp;#182;In this machine problem, we are tasked with implementing search algorithms (BFS, DFS, A*) to find the shortest path (any path in the case of DFS) between two points on a plane that has polygonal obstacles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Satiate: A LD43 Postmortem</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/satiate-a-ld43-postmortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 21:56:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/satiate-a-ld43-postmortem/</guid>
      <description>Just as I joined last April, I joined Ludum Dare this December for Ludum Dare 43.
The Game  The theme for this LD was Sacrifices must be made. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty expansive theme and there was quite a lot of possible game mechanics to build around it, that, for a moment, I was hit by choice-paralysis.
My brainstorm took me through the usual suspects - sacrificing X for Y (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlas Runs: A LD41 Postmortem (with Phaser 3)</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/atlas-runs-a-ld41-postmortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 13:16:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/atlas-runs-a-ld41-postmortem/</guid>
      <description>Ludum Dare is a recurring accelerated video game development event. It is a hackathon-like competition where participants can join a compo (one person creating a game in 48 hours) or the more casual jam (72 hours with optional team members)
I haven&amp;rsquo;t made games for quite some time now, focusing mainly on ReactJS and Web Development, so I thought it was a perfect time to join. While I have a lot of experience programming and joining accelerated development events (winning quite a few in the process), creating a game where I was responsible for everything (I usually work with a team of artists/musicians/etc) would be quite a challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 4R framework - 3 libraries to use in your React app</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/the-4r-framework-3-libraries-to-use-in-your-react-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 10:25:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/the-4r-framework-3-libraries-to-use-in-your-react-app/</guid>
      <description>React fits well right in to the Unix philosophy - it does one thing, and one thing well. It&amp;rsquo;s a beautifully designed, declarative library for building user interfaces.
To write complex React applications however, it would be best to use more libraries than just React in it&amp;rsquo;s lonesome.
The vast and rapidly evolving javascript landscape means there&amp;rsquo;s almost always a library that we can leverage for any given task. Given that, there are 3 libraries I consider essential when making React apps, and I&amp;rsquo;ve consolidated it to this one catchy name because marketing is everything</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Default HOCs for Component Logic</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/use-default-hocs-for-component-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 12:04:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/use-default-hocs-for-component-logic/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps one of the most useful patterns for writing React applications is the classic &amp;ldquo;Container and Presentational Components&amp;rdquo; pattern. Even without knowledge of React, it makes sense - it decomposes concerns between component presentation and logic.
One very useful pattern I&amp;rsquo;ve used to achieve this is by using Higher Order Components to inject default logic to components. This pattern drastically reduces component API boilerplate and more effectively separates implementation and presentational concerns of components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Module Bundling and Webpack in Simple Terms</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/module-bundling-and-webpack-in-simple-terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 21:22:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/module-bundling-and-webpack-in-simple-terms/</guid>
      <description>#chapter-1, #chapter-2__scroll { display: none; position: relative; height: 100vh; width: 100%; } .chapter-1__heading { font-size: 2rem; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 0; max-width: none !important; position: absolute; text-align: center; width: 100%; } .chapter-1__heading-1 { opacity: 1; } .chapter-1__hider-1, .chapter-1__hider-2, .chapter-1__hider-3, .chapter-1__hider-4 { background-color: #002B36; height: 1rem; position: absolute; width: 100%; } .chapter-2__darkener { background-color: gray; opacity: 0.5; position: absolute; height: 30rem; width: 100%; } .chapter-2__code-file { position: absolute; width: 100%; } .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LearnOverpass Final Report</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/learnoverpass-gsoc-2015-final-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 13:40:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/learnoverpass-gsoc-2015-final-report/</guid>
      <description>This year I participated in my 2nd GSOC journey. I worked for the OpenStreetMap Foundation developing an integrated learning platform for their Overpass API which we (me and my mentor) affectionally called LearnOverpass
It&amp;rsquo;s been three months since I started the project, and LearnOverpass is now live and functional - and while the consensus is still out, I&amp;rsquo;m definitely happy with the results!
Exercises, exercises One of the definite &amp;lsquo;killer features&amp;rsquo; we aimed for in LearnOverpass is the inclusion of interactive, playable exercises - with the goal of introducing users, to the Overpass API through active engagement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polishing API Reference: GSOC Weekly Update 4</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/polishing-api-reference-weekly-update-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 11:27:49 +0801</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/polishing-api-reference-weekly-update-4/</guid>
      <description>This is the fourth weekly update for the LearnOverpass Project.
This week&amp;rsquo;s deliverable is to polish the learning platform&amp;rsquo;s API reference.
Modern Sensibilities The changes required for this week required me to flex my design muscles a bit.
Martin&amp;rsquo;s pull request showed my lack of eye for the site&amp;rsquo;s typography, with what me using a 2.5em line-height.
As the line-height issue was fixed, I also decided to pick a more modern typeface to go along with the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porting API Reference: GSOC Weekly Update 3</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/porting-api-reference-weekly-update-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 13:46:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/porting-api-reference-weekly-update-3/</guid>
      <description>This is the third weekly update for the LearnOverpass Project.
This week&amp;rsquo;s deliverable is to &amp;lsquo;port&amp;rsquo; the API reference to the learning platform.
Existing Resources The &amp;lsquo;sales pitch&amp;rsquo; of LearnOverpass has always been &amp;lsquo;a one stop, learning resource for the overpass API&amp;rsquo; - we wanted the site to be the de facto page for learning the Query Language.
To do this properly, we need to make use of, and expand, existing resources of the language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedding Overpass Turbo: GSOC Weekly Update 2</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/embedding-overpass-turbo-weekly-update-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 15:50:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/embedding-overpass-turbo-weekly-update-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the second weekly update for the LearnOverpass Project.
This week&amp;rsquo;s deliverable is to integrate Overpass Turbo inside the learning platform.
  From the get go, we knew we wanted to bring out a REPL-like interface to LearnOverpass - we want to encourage users to actively try and experiment with the Query Language.
The Overpass API guide in the wiki already knew that seeing the results of the query is useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC 2015 Introduction: LearnOverpass</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/gsoc-2015-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 18:52:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/gsoc-2015-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Last year, I worked with the Wordpress organization to integrate socialization and gamification features to the Glotpress translation platform. It&amp;rsquo;s been a fun fulfilling ride, and there are definitely a lot of things that I learned during the project.
This year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been accepted to Google&amp;rsquo;s Summer of Code Program again and I&amp;rsquo;m working with the OpenStreetMap organization to create LearnOverpass!
What is LearnOverpass The Overpass API is a robust API for querying map data, but it&amp;rsquo;s use is still limited due to its beginner-unfriendly documentation and scarce tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Month with Vim</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/my-first-month-with-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 10:48:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/my-first-month-with-vim/</guid>
      <description>Today celebrates my first month with vim.
It also marks the first time I did a custom configuration on my .vimrc. When I said &amp;lsquo;custom&amp;rsquo; it means that it was not just some snippet I found from the internet, it was an actual, personal configuration that made &amp;lsquo;vim&amp;rsquo; my own flavor of &amp;lsquo;vim&amp;rsquo;. This, I think, is the point when someone can say they have graduated from vim noob, to vim user.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>