<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gamedev on Arian&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>//arianv.com/tags/gamedev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gamedev on Arian&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 01:09:26 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//arianv.com/tags/gamedev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlas Runs</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/ludum-dare/ld41/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 01:09:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/ludum-dare/ld41/</guid>
      <description>At first Atlas Shrugged 🤷🏻‍♂️ But now Atlas Runs🏃🏻‍♂️
Atlas Runs is an unconventional platformer/real-time-strategy hybrid where you control both Atlas as he braves the mountains of Thebes, and the townspeople as they manage the town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Satiate</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/ludum-dare/ld43/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:44:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/ludum-dare/ld43/</guid>
      <description>An alien with an insatiable appetiate has attacked your camp. Satiate its cravings using any means necessary&amp;hellip; Even if it means sacrificing your people
 Space - follow (when near person) Z - assign to building (when near building) X - remove all current followers  TIPS:
 Game ramps up in difficulty. Plan accordingly Make propaganda towers to increase human count, then dispensers to allow more to be processed, then hospitals to decrease effects of stress A dispenser produces 50 food and 10 seconds to process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlas Runs: A LD41 Postmortem (with Phaser 3)</title>
      <link>//arianv.com/post/atlas-runs-a-ld41-postmortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 13:16:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//arianv.com/post/atlas-runs-a-ld41-postmortem/</guid>
      <description>Ludum Dare is a recurring accelerated video game development event. It is a hackathon-like competition where participants can join a compo (one person creating a game in 48 hours) or the more casual jam (72 hours with optional team members)
I haven&amp;rsquo;t made games for quite some time now, focusing mainly on ReactJS and Web Development, so I thought it was a perfect time to join. While I have a lot of experience programming and joining accelerated development events (winning quite a few in the process), creating a game where I was responsible for everything (I usually work with a team of artists/musicians/etc) would be quite a challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>